overture 61, uh declare the Danvers
statement
uh to be biblically faithful. Howie, do
you want to start and make a few
comments about that?
>> Sure. I don't like declaring things.
Um
first of all, it's just what the
majority of 2,000 guys in one city did
in one year.
Uh it's not the PCA. It's the guys that
showed up in a majority at that
particular assembly.
Um secondly,
there's a lot of words in the Danvers
statement, and it could be more
biblically faithful
if we tweaked it. Thirdly, it's a
38-year-old document, and it isn't
written as well as it could be. It was
at a particular cultural moment when
radical feminism, I think, was
more threatening than it is now. I know
that
uh
some of our own scholars have critiqued
Danvers. I know that Piper and Grudem
both favor women deacons, and they were
primary authors of Danvers. So,
I just don't think it's a
a wonderful statement. I think it could
be improved, and I don't understand why
we're being asked to declare it as
biblically faithful. Is this supposedly
an alternative to the diaconal overture
or something? I'm a little bit confused.
>> Well, I mean, I would probably, in one
level, I mean, I don't think this is one
that I would want to say no to.
These are the kind of overtures, in a
way, uh
regardless of the of the content that
that I don't like
because
to say no to 61
will automatically go on, you know, the
out into the Twitterverse as, you know,
PCA rejects Danvers uh statement and all
that it uh you know, all that it says.
And so,
in that sense, I I I'm I'm never really
super happy about those because you're
you're sort of
uh in trouble if you do to modify
statement and in trouble if you don't.
And so in that sense none of those
really
excite me terribly much. Um
I do think that
some of the
the principles that are enumerated in it
are you know thought to be
uh you know the argument is is that you
know these are these are principles.
Let's begin with principles and then we
can go to the practical matters
uh and in in in that sort of scheme I'm
I'm 100% in favor of that. I always want
to start with principles before I get to
what we do. So in that sense I don't
have a problem with the issue. I don't
have a problem with Danvers statement.
Uh I mean how he said it's 30 years old.
Well it's echoing biblical language
that's 2,000 years old. So I mean it
it's not the age of it. It's whether or
not it is in fact biblically faithful.
Maybe we can postpone it indefinitely or
something along those lines so we don't
actually have to do anything with it. Uh
because again I don't I don't know that
it's going to I don't think it would
have a problem passing the assembly. I
really don't. I mean the Nashville
statement really didn't either. There
was a lot of debate and discussion over
it and I don't think the assembly is
going to have a hard time declaring it
biblically faithful. Uh it's just a
question of
is that is that going to
speak into the issue that's really
before us. I think principally speaking
um
in so far as the Danvers statement is
biblically faithful we all already
affirm it anyway.
So in that sense I I I understand the
need for it. I understand the point. Um
I'm I'm always opposed to statements
that if we say no to it makes it sound
like we hate something when we just
didn't think it was you know so all of
those things wrapped up together uh I'm
not sure how to deal with it but that's
kind of where I'm at.
>> Well I I think we could uh
deny the overture and say
uh
we deny because it's not our the part of
our church's calling to hear and endorse
statements of other parts of the church
or institutions. We have enough to do to
care for our own house. I'd like to shut
this down. No more Nashville, no more
Denver.